# LAUREN POWERS | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a Software Engineer with a passion for creating and building. My 12 years of experience in financial operations have helped me turn problem-solving and crisis management into everyday practice. My collaborative and determined approach enables me to see challenges as opportunities to learn and grow.

### **SKILLS**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Git | GitHub | API | React.js | Python | Django | Node.js | MongoDB | Mongoose | Express | SQL Postgres | Flask

## **PROJECTS**

**Game of Trivia** - <u>GibHub/Live Site</u> - Front end multiple choice game of trivia written in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. The user will select an answer out of four choices. There are 10 questions, each worth 10 points.

**Simpsons Quote Generator** - <u>Github/Live Site</u> - A Simpsons quote generator to make you feel nostalgic. A responsive web application using React.js. The Simpsons Quote API was implemented to fetch images, quotes, and character names.

**B-Side Music** - <u>GitHub/Live Site</u> - CRUD functional database of lesser-known musicians and artists. Collaborated with a team of 5 developers to create a full-stack web application using Mongoose, Express, React.js, and Node.js.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

New York, NY

Software Engineering Fellow

Sept 2022- Dec 2022

- Built fully responsive front-end web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and third party API-integrations.
- Developed full-stack applications and designed REST APIs with full CRUD functionality using React, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, SQL, PeeWee, Flask, and Django.

#### JP Morgan Chase Bank, N.A.

New York, NY

Assistant Branch Manager- Operations

September 2021- March 2022

Lead Associate Operations

June 2018 - September 2021

Personal Banker

August 2010 - June 2018

- Managed, trained, and mentored 15+ employees on standard operating procedures, which led to high annual branch review scores.
- Scored 97%+ on three annual branch audits resulting in increased branch peer ranking.
- Led and developed branch staff to meet customer service needs resulting in increased overall satisfaction survey scores by 10%-15%.
- Provided leadership, feedback, and coaching on employee performance increasing branch review scores by up to 20% annually.
- Collaborated with the Branch Manager to direct sales and all aspects of branch operation, including loss control, compliance, customer retention, and audit standards.
- Educated clients to increase the usage of technology self-service options such as Chase Mobile App, Chase.com, and ATMs exceeding branch score-card metrics.

## **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly** New York, NY - Software Engineering Immersive Certificate | 2022 **State University of New York - College at Purchase** - Purchase, NY - Bachelor of the Arts - Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal Studies - The Arts